<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sylvain Verly</title>
    <link>http://sylvainv.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sylvain Verly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Sylvain Verly</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>http://sylvainv.github.io/project/postgresql-extension-pg-salesforce-id/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sylvainv.github.io/project/postgresql-extension-pg-salesforce-id/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The plugin helps database administrators who use PostgreSQL and Salesforce IDS in their database to have a more efficient internal representation that helps reduce space and time to compute comparison between two ids as opposed to using a text type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sylvainv/pg-salesforce-id&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-github&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dev stack:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PostgreSQL,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PostgreSQL extension,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C++&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuodata</title>
      <link>http://sylvainv.github.io/project/nuodata/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sylvainv.github.io/project/nuodata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I founded Nuodata.io: a SaaS platform and open source open source project. It is based on PostgreSQL and Node.js. I am responsible for the development and the architecture of the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/nuodata/nuodata-db-api&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-github&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; nuodata-db-api&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/nuodata/nuodata-server&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-github&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; nuodata-server&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nuodata.io&#34;&gt;http://nuodata.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal is to use tables and views as your API endpoints, for CRUD operations. The goal is to shift a lot of development to the database to save time and have a more reliable data and system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web stack:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PostgreSQL,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Node.js,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Json Web Token&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Digital Ocean&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manta: a friendly user interface to display query results from a Semantic Web search engine</title>
      <link>http://sylvainv.github.io/project/manta-semantic-web-search-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sylvainv.github.io/project/manta-semantic-web-search-engine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Semantic Web is a set of technologies that aims to make data available and easily readable for machine via the web. Unlike the classic Web where resources are pages pub- lished using natural language and some structured information, resources in the Semantic Web are organized formally using a set of languages developed by the W3C. Search engines are crucial for discovering those resources. Sindice is a semantic web search engine that crawls the Web looking for those kind of information. Its interface is however not intended for regular users, like most Semantic Web search engine. This is the principle behind Manta . Manta intends to make a friendly user interface for search engine using Sindice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sylvainv.github.io/docs/manta-semantic-web-search-engine.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-file-pdf-o&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Full dissertation document&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NASA&#39;s SAFER B-method</title>
      <link>http://sylvainv.github.io/project/b-method-safer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sylvainv.github.io/project/b-method-safer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The objective of the project was to develop an implementation of the SAFER backpack propulsion system using formal methods. SAFER backpack was designed by NASA. It helps an astronaut, in case of accidental separation from the spacecraft during an EVA (Extra Vehicular Activity), to return to his space shuttle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project goal was to develop a working software system for the backpack, from the NASA specification document and using the B-method. The software should response properly (as stated in the specification) to inputs given by the astronaut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A key objective is to develop a deep understanding of how the B-method works, its strengths and limitations. The SAFER specification has been previously analysed using two other formal methods, i.e. PVS and VDM. Using the SAFER example it will be possible to compare the results of using B-Method with the results of these two previous approaches carried out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sylvainv.github.io/docs/nasa-safer-using-b-method.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-file-pdf-o&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Full dissertation document&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
